My name is Christine Marquette and I'm a registered dietitian with the Austin Regional Clinic and I'm going to talk to you about hormones for weight loss.
In the last 5 to 10 years there's actually been a lot of research into various hormones and how they may affect weight loss.
One area of research has involved the hormone oxygen modulin and this particular hormone is found in the gut and in some of the preliminary research when it was injected into overweight or obese people, they did lose more weight than those taking placebo.
The exact mechanism hasn't really been identified.
In addition, they really were not sure if these people were losing actual body fat or actually just losing body fluids.
So again, very preliminary research on that particular hormone.
Its not being widely used yet.
Another hormone that's been studied more is growth hormone.
Now this hormone it has been identified that when people that are overweight or obese have been injected with it, they actually do reduce their body fat.
They lose weight in the method of losing body fat.
In addition, it seems to curb their appetite.